Harry Hamlin

Harry Hamlin Seattle, WA

Director of Operations

541.760.9005 harryhamlin@gmail.com

Profile

Director of Operations with years of success overseeing the operations and staff of a mid-sized (\$5MM/40 employees) company, managing both day-to-day operations and long-term growth. Previous leadership experience on Mt Everest and in other outdoor industry sectors.

Experience

International Mountain Guides/Director of Operations

January 2021-Present

- -Oversee daily operations and manage a multi-leveled and diverse staff.
- -Consistently meet and exceed goals, oversee growth of 33% in 2021.
- -Coordinate hiring, training, performance evaluation, and growth opportunities for a large (40+) staff.
- -Implement and develop a pay structure designed to encourage results-oriented work and professional development, resulting in a measurable increase of workplace satisfaction.
- -Implement a multi-platform customer data collection system, using AirTable, Docusign and Zapier, leading to a measurable increase in customer satisfaction.
- -Lead a team in overhauling our back-end email system leading to a higher degree of security and allowing for the implementation of a CRM system.
- -Level set career expectations to massive company change
- -Lead a well-rounded team by facilitating clear and present communication, through quantitative performance feedback and outlining clear expectations of work duties.
- -Implement a complex feedback system for staff performance targets.
- -Manage an administrative team collecting sensitive information and oversee dissemination to staff.
- -Work closely with governmental agencies, physicians, and private industry writing and implementing dynamic Covid-19 policies.
- -Work closely with governmental agencies in operating within permit boundaries while still maximizing performance and financial outcomes.
- -Create and execute marketing strategy and content.
- -Oversee the growth and implementation of retail strategy, including buying.

International Mountain Guides/Senior Supervising Guide, Everest Exped. Team Leader June 2016-January 2021

- -Oversee a small-to-medium-sized staff (2-10) in high-risk scenarios.
- -Manage the risk, expectations, and well-being of staff and clientele in hyper objective-based climbing guiding.
- -Balance client-facing and staff-facing communication when implementing strategy.
- -Assist in high-hazard rescue when required.

Other Leadership Experience

Crystal Mountain Ski Patrol/Shift Supervisor/ June 2014-January 2019 **AIARE**/Avalanche Education Course Leader/ November 2017-Present **Seattle Bouldering Project**/Programs Manager/ April 2014-November 2014

Education